《电锯惊魂》
救命啊！快来人啊
Help! Someone help me!
有人在吗？
Is someone there?
靠 我搞不好死了
Oh, shit. I probably dead.
- 你没死 - 是谁？
- You're not dead. - Who's that?
把灯打开！
Turn on the lights!
我也想
Wish I could.
搞什么？这是哪里？
What the fuck is going on? Where am I?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
那是什么味道？
What is that smell?
我没看到呀
I don't see a thing, asshole.
我靠
Shit!
救命啊！
Help!
不会有人听见的
No one can hear you.
- 这是什么状况？- 你冷静一点
- What the fuck is this? - Calm down. Just calm down.
- 你有受伤吗？- 我不知道 有吧
- Are you hurt? - I don't know. Yeah!
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
我叫莫名其妙 你呢？这是怎么回事？
My name is very fucking confused. What's your name? What's going on here?
我叫劳伦斯·戈登 我是医生
My name is Lawrence Gordon. I'm a doctor.
我也是在这里醒来
I just woke up here. Just like you.
- 你认得他吗？- 不认得
- Recognize that man? - No.
- 你是怎么来的？- 不知道
- Do you have any idea how you got here? - No.
- 你记得的上一件事呢？- 没什么
- What's the last thing you remember? - Nothing.
我上床睡觉 然后就沦落到这里
I went to bed in my shit-hole apartment and woke up in an actual shit-hole.
你呢？
What about you?
没什么好说的
There's not much to tell really.
我下了班要回家 其他都不记得了
I was on my way home from work and I don't remember anything else.
我没看过死人 亲眼看差好多
First dead body I've ever seen. Look different in real life.
动也不动
They don't move.
看来
From the looks of these chains…
某人也不希望我们走远
someone didn't want us to go very far either.
- 你有看到伤口吗？- 什么？
- Can you see any scars? - What?
他们都这样 绑架下药
This is what they do. They kidnap you and drug you…
把你留在浴缸里盗卖你的肾
and before you know it, you're in a bathtub and your kidneys are on eBay.
- 没人取走你的肾 - 那么远你哪知道？
- No one has taken your kidneys. - How can you tell from way over there?
因为那样会痛不欲生 甚至早就死了
Because you'd either be in terrible agony or you'd be dead by now.
相信我
Trust me.
- 你是外科医生吗？- 没错
- What are you, a surgeon? - Yeah.
所以 你到底说不说名字？
So, you going to tell me your name or what?
亚当
Adam.
Well, Adam…
我们必须做的
what we need to do…
是想清楚来龙去脉
is start thinking about why we are here.
下手的人大可杀了我们
Whoever brought us here could've killed us by now.
但是没有
But they didn't.
他们一定有目的
They must want something from us.
是什么目的？
Question is what.
- 那个钟 - 怎样？
- That clock. - What about it?
- 它是全新的 - 所以呢？
- It's brand-new. - So?
显然有人要我们知道时间
So somebody obviously wanted us to know the time.
等等 我应该够得到门
Wait. I think I might be able to reach the door.
那是什么？
What is that?
我在问你
Excuse me.
- 是录音带 - 在哪里找到的？
- It's a tape. - Where did you find it?
我的口袋里
It was in my pocket.
上面写 「放出来」
It says "Play me."
快开啊
Come on.
扔过来
Throw it over here.
开不了？
No?
- 用衬衫捞 - 什么
- Use your shirt. - What?
你的衬衫
Your shirt.
快啊
Come on.
行不通
It won't work.
找一下 一定有东西可用
Look around. There must be something else you can use.
- 什么也没有 - 一定有
- There's nothing. - There must be something.
加油 你行的
Come on. You can do it.
快点 再试一次
Come on. Again.
亚当 起床了 你可能在想这是哪里
Rise and shine, Adam. You're probably wondering where you are.
我来告诉你
I'll tell you where you might be.
这可能是你的葬身之地
You might be in the room that you die in.
过去你都一直躲在暗处
Up until now, you simply sat in the shadows…
窥看别人的生活
watching others live out their lives.
偷窥狂都怎么看待自己
What do voyeurs see when they look into the mirror?
你是个奇怪的综合体
Now, I see you as a strange mix…
愤怒却又冷漠
of someone angry and yet apathetic.
不过主要是可悲
But mostly just pathetic.
所以今天你要看着自己死
So are you going to watch yourself die today, Adam?
或是设法阻止
Or do something about it?
我不懂
I don't get it.
把录音机扔过来
Throw me the player.
不要 你把带子扔过来
No. You throw me your tape.
听着 我们想逃走就得合作
Look, we're going to have to work together if we want to get out of here.
快扔过来
Now, just throw it to me.
摔坏了怎么办？你扔过来
I'm not going to risk breaking it. You throw me your tape.
戈登医生 我来叫醒你
Dr. Gordon. This is your wake-up call.
你每天的工作就是告诉别人
Every day of your working life, you have given people the news…
他们快死了
that they are going to die soon.
现在你将成为死因
Now you will be the cause of death.
你的目标是杀死亚当
Your aim in this game is to kill Adam.
时限是6点之前
You have until 6:00 on the clock to do it.
现场还有第三个人
There's a man in the room with you.
当血液中含有巨毒 唯有自尽
When there is that much poison in your blood, the only thing left to do…
才能解脱
is shoot yourself.
胜利的途径
There are ways to win this…
就藏在周遭
hidden all around you.
记住 X标示了藏宝处
Just remember: "X" marks the spot for the treasure.
要是你没及时杀死亚当
If you do not kill Adam by 6:00…
艾丽森和黛安娜就会死
then Alison and Diana will die, Dr. Gordon.
我则会让你在这里腐烂
And I'll leave you in this room to rot.
让游戏开始吧
Let the game begin.
给我 快点
Give me that. Now.
艾丽森和黛安娜就会死
…then Alison and Diana will die, Dr. Gordon.
我则会让你在这里腐烂
And I will leave you in this room to rot.
知道是谁吗？
Any idea who that is?
让游戏开始吧
Let the game begin.
- 他认识我们 - 来吧
- He knows us. - Come on.
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
可能是恶作剧对吧？
Probably a joke, right?
让游戏开始吧
Let the game begin.
你听
Listen.
遵从你的心
Follow your heart.
这话是什么意思？
What the hell does "follow your heart" mean?
在那里 你旁边的马桶上
There, right next to you, on the toilet.
快啊
Come on.
- 有东西吗？- 没有硬的
- Anything? - No solids.
把水箱打开
Take off the lid.
早知道先找这里
I really wish I had checked in there first.
是什么？
What is it?
另一把给我好吗？
Mind passing me the other one?
干！妈的
Fuck!
他不是要我们锯断铁链
He doesn't want us to cut through our chains.
他要我们锯断脚
He wants us to cut through our feet.
我可能知道是谁干的
I think I may know who's done this to us.
- 你说什么？- 我并不认识他
- What did you say? - It's not someone I know personally.
只是知道他
It's just someone I know of.
那就快说 是谁？
Jesus Christ! Tell me. Who is it?
就我所知
The last I heard…
警方还没捉到他
the police still hadn't caught him.
我之所以知道 是因为我是嫌犯
And the only reason I know that is because I was a suspect.
我从头说起
I'll start from the beginning.
这一个死很久了 至少3周
This one's not fresh anymore. At least three weeks out.
死者是46岁男性
Victim's a 46-year-old male.
死于大出血 主要是大腿动脉
Died of massive blood loss. Mostly through the femoral artery.
他硬钻过有刺的铁丝网
He started at the back of the cage…
居然还钻了
and tunneled his way through that razor wire so fast…
那么远
it's amazing he got as far as he did.
伤口深到胃酸流了满地
Cut himself so deep, we found traces of stomach acid on the floor.
我们还找到这个
We also found this.
保罗 你好
Hello, Paul.
你是身心健全的中产阶级
You're a perfectly healthy, sane, middle-class male.
上个月却用刮胡刀割腕自杀
Yet, last month, you ran a straight razor across your wrists.
你割腕是真的想寻死
Did you hurt yourself because you truly wanted to die…
还是只想引人注意？
or did you just want some attention?
今晚 我拭目以待
Tonight, you'll show me.
讽刺的是如果你想死 只须留在这里
The irony is that if you want to die you just have to stay where you are.
想活 就得再次伤害自己
But if you want to live, you'll have to cut yourself again.
设法钻过铁丝网到门口
One path through the razor wire to the door.
不过要快 3点门会上锁
But hurry. At 3:00 that door will lock…
到时这里就成了你的墓室
and then this room becomes your tomb.
你会为了活命流多少血？
How much blood will you shed to stay alive, Paul?
门上有计时器 3点前都开着
The door was on a timer. It was unlocked until 3:00.
然后就关上了 限时2小时
Then it snapped shut. He was given two hours.
拼图的形状
Jigsaw piece.
这里有得忙了
I think I'm gonna be here for a while.
报纸开始称他为「拼图杀人狂」
The newspapers started calling him the "Jigsaw killer."
事实上 严格来说他
Actually, technically speaking, he is…
不是凶手
not really a murderer.
他没有杀过人
He never killed anyone.
他都让死者杀死自己
He finds ways for his victims to kill themselves.
马克 要是你真的病重
Hello, Mark, if you're so sick…
为何我拍到你经常外出
then why do I have so many photos of you up and about?
让我们来检验你的病情
Let's put your so-called illness to the test.
你被注射了慢性毒药
Right now, there is a slow-acting poison in your veins.
解毒剂在保险箱里
The antidote is inside the safe.
至于密码
The combination to the safe…
就写在墙上
is written on the wall.
赶快输入密码 走路小心
Hurry up and program it in. But watch your step.
还有 你身上淋了易燃物
By the way, that's flammable substance smeared on your body.
换作是我就会小心火烛
So I would be careful with that candle, if I were you…
救命啊
Help.
否则被你伤害的人们
…or all the people you've burned with your act…
将会大呼痛快
just might have their revenge.
还有一个发现 其实是两个
I found something else. Well, two things actually.
有人透过这个洞往里看
There was someone standing outside here watching through this peephole.
看来拼图杀人狂 喜欢近距离观赏他的变态游戏
Looks like our friend Jigsaw likes to book himself front row seats to his sick games.
上次他也在现场
He was there at the last one as well.
但这次他遗留了手电筒
Only this time, he left us his penlight.
- 立刻采集指纹 - 知道了
- Get a rush on the prints. - Copy that.
好的 病患有无法开刀的前叶肿瘤
Okay. This patient has an inoperable frontal lobe tumor…
一开始是结肠癌
extending across the midline. Started as a colon cancer.
病患到院接受检查
The patient has come in for a standard checkup…
观察结果病情逐渐恶化
by which we are able to monitor the rate at which his condition is declining.
- 病患有 - 他叫约翰·戈登医生
- The patient had… - His name is John, Dr. Gordon.
这个人很有意思
He's a very interesting person.
谢谢你的提醒 赛普
Thank you for that information, Zep.
本院护理员和病患非常有感情
As you can see, our orderlies form very special bonds with the patients.
- 我们继续 病患 - 戈登医生 请联络传呼员
- Continuing on, the patient… - Dr. Gordon, please page the operator.
有人不要我说下去 失陪
Obviously, someone doesn't want me to tell you what the patient has. Excuse me.
戈登医生 泰普警探
Dr. Gordon, I'm Det. Tapp…
辛警探 重案组
this is Det. Sing. City Homicide.
好傲人的学历
Very impressive.
谢谢 我尽力而为
Thank you. I do my best.
- 抱歉打扰你工作 - 不要紧
- Sorry to interrupt you while you're working. - That's fine.
有什么事吗？
How can I help you, gentlemen?
你昨晚
Tell us where you were…
11点到1点在哪里？
between the hours of 11:00 p. m. And 1:00 a. m. Last night, Doctor.
为什么要问？
Why is it that you're interested?
我们想请教几件事
We'd like to ask you a few questions about it.
回局里问话对你比较好
For your sake, I think it's best if we do it down at the station.
请你走一趟
Would you like to follow us there?
恐怕没办法
No. I'm afraid that's quite out of the question.
我不能扔下工作 我太太又开了车
I can't just leave, I have work to do. Plus, my wife has the car today.
没关系 我们可以载你 医生
That's okay. You can ride with us, Doc.
抱歉 请再说一次 究竟是什么事？
I'm sorry, you'll have to tell me again. What is this all about?
这是你的吗？
Is this yours, Doctor?
你不知道手电筒怎么会在那里
So you have no idea how your penlight showed up at the murder scene?
当然不知道
Of course not.
你昨晚到底在做什么？
I'll have to ask. What were you doing last night?
和某人见面
I was seeing someone.
谁？
Who?
- 要是你不告诉我 - 一个不是病患的人 好吗？
- Look, if you can't be honest with me… - I was visiting someone. It wasn't a patient.
我该怎么办？
What am I gonna do?
身为你的律师和朋友
Well, as your lawyer and your friend, my advice to you is to bite the bullet…
我建议你乖乖提出不在场证明
and give them your alibi now.
拖久了没人会信
Because no one is going to believe you later.
那是5个月前的事
That was five months ago.
他想陷害我
He tried to set me up for murder.
好了 你的不在场证明没问题
Okay. We checked your alibi. It holds up.
那好 我可以走了吗？
Good. Can I go home now?
有一名幸存的受害者
We have one of the victims who managed to escape.
希望你能留下来听听她的证词
Want to know if you wouldn't mind sticking around and listening to her testimony?
- 也许你会想起什么 - 我很想帮忙
- Maybe it'll trigger something. - I'd like to help really but…
拜托你了
We'd really appreciate it.
- 只有她没死 - 好吧
- She's the only one who made it. - Okay.
亚曼妲
Amanda…
你慢慢说
in your own time…
你最先想起什么？
tell me the first thing you remember.
我醒来 满嘴血腥味
I woke up. All I could taste was blood…
满嘴血腥味
and metal.
亚曼妲 你好
Hello, Amanda.
你不认识我 但我认识你
You don't know me, but I know you.
我想玩个游戏 你输的下场是
I want to play a game. Here's what happens if you lose.
那个头罩钩住了你的上下颔
The device you're wearing is hooked into your upper and lower jaws.
计时器一响
When the timer at the back goes off…
你的嘴就会被扯开
your mouth will be permanently ripped open.
和捕兽器正好相反
Think of it like a reverse bear trap.
我示范给你看
Here, I'll show you.
只有一把钥匙能打开它
There is only one key to open the device.
在旁边的尸体肚子里
It's in the stomach of your dead cellmate.
你看了就知道我没骗你
Look around, Amanda. Know that I'm not lying.
动作快
You better hurry up.
是死是活 赶快决定
Live or die. Make your choice.
然后我看到尸体
And then I saw the body.
有一把刀
There was a knife.
他被注射大量麻醉剂
He'd been injected with an opiate overdose.
不能动也没感觉
He couldn't move or feel much of anything.
- 你是说他还活着？- 当时是的
- You mean he was alive? - Was.
你拿掉头罩之后呢？
What happened after you took it off?
恭喜你 你还活着
Congratulations. You are still alive.
人活着多半不知感激
Most people are so ungrateful to be alive.
你以后不会了
But not you. Not anymore.
其实你有毒瘾 对不对？
You are, in fact, a drug addict. Isn't that right, Mandy?
所以他才找上你吗？
Do you think that is why he picked you?
你觉得感激吗？
Are you grateful, Mandy?
他 帮了我
He helped me.
- 你确定是他？- 我确定
- Are you sure it's him? - Yeah, I'm sure.
谁知道是真是假 搞不好是你搞的鬼
How do I know you're telling the truth? You can be the one that put me in this room.
- 我跟你的处境一模一样 - 错 才不一样
- I'm in exactly the same situation you are in. - Wrong.
你有我没有的线索 你知道对方是谁
You've got one thing I don't: Information. You know who did this.
你知道对方是谁
Now you either tell me what is really going on…
否则我划花你 我
or I'll cut you with this. You hear me? I'll cut…
- 怎么了？- 这是双面镜
- What? - It's a two-way mirror.
我看得见你们
I can see you.
这是真人实境秀吗？
So that's what this is. Reality TV.
别看我 我也爱莫能助
Don't look at me. I can't help you.
你听得见吗？我玩得超爽
Can you hear me in there? I'm having a blast.
打手枪还爽
This is the most fun I've had without lubricant.
你一定要全都录
Make sure you're getting everything.
你扔它也没用
That's not going to do anything.
- 你要让它拍下去？- 你阻止不了的
- You just want to leave it running on us? - He won't stop it.
所以铁链锯不断
That's why we can't cut through these chains.
所以铁链锯不断 玻璃砸不破
It's why you won't break that glass.
每个角度他都先想到了
Every possible angle has been pre-thought out by him.
你好像很崇拜他
You sound like you admire this prick.
要对付一件事得找出破绽
To overcome something, you have to understand what a perfect engine it is.
对抗疾病就是
That's how you fight disease.
录音带叫我们找 X
Now the tape told us to find an "X."
X 一定在这里 帮我找出来
That "X" has to be somewhere in this room. Help me find it.
你怎么这么冷静 你的家人
How can you be the calm doctor-guy when your wife and kid are out there?
也在他手上 可能正在受苦
He's got them, too. He could be doing anything to them right now.
- 你有想到吗？- 我正在想
- Are you thinking about that? - I am thinking about that.
我在想我最后对女儿说的话
I've been thinking about the last thing I said to my daughter.
黛安娜？你没事吧？
Diana. Honey, are you okay?
- 你听得见吗？- 妈咪
- Can you hear me? - Mommy.
- 乖 怎么了？- 我房里有人
- What is it, sweet pea? - There's a man in my room.
你确定不是你在乱想？
Honey, are you sure he's not just hiding in your imagination?
他跟我说话
He talked to me.
- 好 我去检查 - 我要爹地
- Okay, I'll come and check your room. - I want Daddy.
他会捉住那个人
He'll get the scary man.
那好吧 走吧
All right, if you want. Come on.
劳瑞 打扰了 你女儿又作恶梦了
Larry, sorry to bother you, but your daughter had a bad dream again.
等一下
Just a minute.
她要你去检查房间
She wants you to check her room.
我先写完这段
Just got to finish this paragraph.
走吧 我们自己去
Come on, sweetie, I'll go check with you.
不用 我好了
Yep. I'm done.
看吧 根本没有人
See, there's no one in your room.
根本没有坏蛋 你可以睡了吗？
There's no such thing as the bad man. Now can you go to sleep?
- 我还是好怕 - 是吗？
- I'm still scared. - You are?
把脚伸出来
Give me your tootsy.
好大一只脚
What a big tootsy.
记得吗？
Remember this one?
这只小猪上市场 这只小猪留在家
"This little piggy went to market This little piggy stayed home.
这只小猪吃烤牛 这只小猪饿肚皮
"This little piggy had roast beef This little piggy had none.
这只小猪一路吱吱叫着回家
"This little piggy went 'Whee' all the way home"
我讨厌它
I hate that thing.
我得进医院 当医生就是这样
I have to go to work, sweetheart. You know what Daddy's job is like.
来吧
Now, come on.
乖 赶快睡觉觉好吗？
Let's see. Try and get some sleep now, okay?
你不会离开我们吧？
You're not going to leave us, are you, Daddy?
什么？
What?
你在说什么？离开你和妈咪？
What are you talking about? You mean, leave you and Mommy?
当然不会 我绝不会那么做
No, sweetheart. I would never do that.
- 你哪来的念头？- 也没有
- Who gave you that idea? - No one.
没那回事 好吗？
It's not true. Okay?
我有多爱你？
How much do I love you?
- 这么爱 - 没错
- Love you very much. - Very much. That's right.
- 晚安 小宝贝 - 爹地晚安
- Good night, sweetie. - Good night, Daddy.
- 明天来念你最喜欢的故事 - 好
- Tomorrow, I'll read your favorite story. - Okay.
我不知有多少时间来做这个
I don't know how much longer I can do this.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你怎么能这样故做快乐？
How can you walk through life pretending you're happy?
- 我很快乐啊 - 胡说八道
- I am happy. - That is complete bullshit.
你发飙恨我
I'd rather you break down and tell me that you hated me.
都还比较有感情
At least there'd be some passion in it.
你要看她吗？
Would you like to see her?
- 她很漂亮 - 谢谢
- She's beautiful. - Thank you.
- 你们还想生吗？- 我们讨论过 不过
- You gonna have any more kids? - We've talked about it, but…
目前一个就忙不过来了
with our schedules, it's difficult enough to concentrate on one.
那你老婆呢？
So where is the lucky wife?
背后还有一张
There's another picture behind the one you're looking at.
是我的最爱 因为是合照
It's my favorite one because we're all in it together.
通常我都要拍照
Someone, usually me, has to hold the camera…
所以总是少了我
which means I'm always missing from the photos.
- 照片 照片不在 - 什么？
- It's not here. - What?
没有你说的那张照片
This photo you're talking about is not here.
- 真的？你确定？- 确定
- Really? Are you sure? - Yeah.
一定是他拿走了
He must have taken it.
你怎么能这样故做快乐？
How can you walk through life pretending you're happy?
- 我很快乐啊 - 胡说八道
- I am happy. - That is complete bullshit.
你发飙恨我
I'd rather you break down and tell me that you hated me.
At least there'd be some passion in it.
回来再说好吗？
We can talk about this later, okay?
你走吧
Just leave.
晚安 小女孩
Good night, little girl.
黛安娜
Diana!
妈咪
Mommy!
妈咪 救命啊
你走开！不要靠近她
Don't do that! Leave her!
你这个变态！
You little man…
我看见你了
I see you.
戈登医生知道你在他家吗？
Does Dr. Gordon know you're at home with his wife?
你一定知道些什么
I know you know something.
你在他家做什么？
What are you doing there?
等他吗？我也在等他
Waiting for the doctor? I'm waiting for the doctor, too.
我不该放你走的
I know that she'll let you go.
你不知道手电筒怎么会在那里
So you have no idea how your penlight showed up at the murder scene?
不在场证明 没问题
We checked your alibi. It holds up.
对不对 医生？
Isn't that right?
我不该放你走的
I know that she'll let you go.
到了
Here we are.
那个女人的遭遇真骇人听闻
That was quite an amazing story that poor woman told.
抱歉无法帮上更多忙
I'm sorry I can't be of more help to your investigation.
上周有个牙医被捕
You know, we arrested a dentist last week…
他有恋童癖
who liked to play with kids a bit too much.
他住在两条街外
He lived two blocks from here.
那里的污水系统和这里相通
The sewer lines run under this neighborhood, too, Doctor.
亚曼妲 你好
Hello, Amanda.
你不认识我 但我认识你
You don't know me, but I know you.
我想玩个游戏 你输的下场是
I want to play a game. Here's what happens if you lose.
头罩背面有计时器
There's a timer at the back of the device you're wearing.
时间一到
When the timer goes off…
你的嘴就会被扯开
your mouth will be permanently ripped open.
你们下去我会赶上来的
I'll catch you guys down there.
和捕兽器正好相反
Think of it like a reverse bear trap.
我来示范
I'll show you.
我要去喝一杯 你要来吗？
We're gonna go down to The Grill, go get a beer. You wanna come?
- 不了 谢谢 - 我都会问一声
- I don't think so. Thanks, anyway. - You know I always ask.
只有一把钥匙
There's only one key…
慢慢欣赏
I'll leave you to have fun here then.
在旁边的尸体肚子里
It's in the stomach of your dead cellmate.
不是我没大没小
I don't mean for this to be disrespectful.
也许你该交个女朋友
Maybe you should find yourself a girlfriend.
在旁边的尸体肚子里
It's in the stomach of your dead cellmate.
你看了
Look around.
你看了就知道我没骗你
Look around, Amanda. Know that I'm not lying.
动作快
You better hurry up.
等等 辛
Wait! Sing.
- 快回来 - 什么事？
- Get back here. - What?
记得118街吗？
Remember 118th Street?
K2K帮
K2K.
地盘在四条街外
That gang's territory was only about four blocks.
然后你听
Listen to this.
查出
We gotta check the records…
这两周那一带的火警纪录
from all fire emergencies that occurred there in the last two weeks.
快去
Go. Right now.
17号星期二晚上
On the night of Tuesday, the 17th…
冥河街213号的背面失火
we got a fire alarm going off in the rear wing of 213, Stygian Street.
那里原本是橱窗假人工厂
It's an old listing. Used to be a mannequin factory.
足以申请搜索票吗？
Think we have enough for a warrant now?
谁说要申请了？
Who said anything about a warrant?
- 现在要去？- 不好吗？
- Right now? - Why not?
当然好 至少有黑暗做掩护
At least we'll have the cover of darkness.
别人也是
Yeah, well, so will anybody else.
逮到你了
I got you.
这是什么玩意？
What the hell is this?
妈的
Shit!
- 等一下 - 怎样？
- Sing. - What?
- 先观察动静 - 为什么？他完蛋了
- Let's see what's he's gonna do. - Why? We got him.
我想先确定 先等一下
We don't know what he looks like. Lets see what he's gonna do.
我才不要
No fucking way.
辛 我要制服他
Fuck that. I'm gonna take him.
搞什么？妈的
What the fuck? Shit!
杰夫 你已经醒了？
Awake already, Jeff?
下次要用更强的药 别哭
I need more powerful tranquilizers next time. Don't cry.
我让你活得有意义
I've given your life a purpose.
这是个很伟大的实验
You're a test subject for something greater than yourself.
- 不准动！警察 - 站住不准动
- Freeze! Police. - Hold it right there! Don't move!
把手举起来
Put your fucking hands in the air!
你们必须选择
Now you'll make a choice.
20秒后这个人将一命呜呼
In 20 seconds, the life of this man will be ended.
- 闭嘴跪下 - 快关掉
- Shut up and get down here. - Turn it off.
辛 关机器 我来搞定他
Sing, stop that thing. I'm taking this bastard down.
快点
Move!
- 怎么关？- 叫他关掉
- How do you turn it off? - Tell him how to stop it!
- 得用钥匙 - 在哪里？
- One key will unlock it. - Where is it?
- 在那个盒子里 - 盒子？
- It's in the box. - Box?
- 是哪一把？- 快告诉他
- Which key? - Tell him which key it is.
- 时间快没了 - 闭嘴跪下 混蛋
- Time is running out. - Get down here right now, asshole!
哪件事比较重要？
What's more important to you, Officer…
逮捕我 还是另一条人命？
arresting me, or the life of another human being?
快跪下 混蛋
Get down on your knees!
- 天哪！- 救命！
- Jesus! - Help me!
我确实有病
Yes, I am sick, Officer.
泰普！有好多钥匙
Tapp, it's none of the keys here!
我正在受病魔侵袭
Sick from the disease eating away at me inside.
我恨身在福中不知福的人
Sick of people who don't appreciate their blessings.
嘲弄他人痛苦的人
Sick of those who scoff at the suffering of others.
我受够了
I'm sick of all.
不！泰普 妈的
No! Tapp. Shit.
我马上回来 好吗？
I'll be back. Okay?
站住 否则我开枪
Freeze! Or I'll shoot.
我让你 让你跪下了
Got you on your knees.
然后你跑了
You're running.
你吓跑了 因为你被逮到了
You're running scared because we had you.
我要破案
I'm going to close this case.
我们要破案 对吧 辛？
We've closed it. We're right, Sing.
我们要破案
We're going to close this thing.
X 标示了藏宝处
"X" marks the spot.
我们得再找一次
We should search this room again.
你在干什么？
What are you doing over there?
老兄
Excuse me.
就因为我们俩在一个房间里…
Just because I'm stuck in this room with you…
我不必每10秒就向你回报
doesn't mean I have to report to you every 10 seconds.
我们没理由不互相帮忙
I really don't see the point in us not helping one other.
你想怎样？我行动不便
What do you want me to do? I'm on a leash.
所以我们才要讨论思考
That's exactly why we need to talk. We need to think.
我在思考啊
I am thinking.
那就别让我瞎猜
Then don't keep me in the dark about what you're thinking.
- 关灯 - 什么？
- Turn off the lights. - What?
- 快关灯 - 为什么？
- Turn them off, now, please! - Why?
总之先关个灯
Just turn them off for a second.
天哪 在你背后
Jesus! Behind you.
- 之前怎么没看到？- 因为之前灯没落下来
- How come we didn't see that before? - The lights in here hadn't charged it.
那一定是要吸光的夜光漆
It must be glow-in-the-dark paint or something.
- 快打开 - 锁住了
- Open it. - It's locked.
我的信封里的钥匙呢？
The key. The one from my envelope. Where is it?
拿去
Where the fuck… Here.
手机 世上最赞的发明
Cell phone. The most beautiful invention on this planet.
那是第二赞的发明
Make that second most beautiful invention.
- 给我 - 你疯啦？
- Give me that. - Are you joking?
你要抽这房里的烟？
You're gonna put something we found in this room in your mouth?
我愿意冒险 让我得肺癌吧
Yes. I'm willing to risk it. Give me that sweet cancer.
嘘 别说话 给我一根烟
I don't care, I really don't. Give me one of those.
我保证香烟没有毒
The cigarettes are harmless, I promise.
抽烟抽出人命才有毒
Smoking is only poisonous when it ends in bloodshed.
你不必用枪也能杀亚当
Think about this: You don't need a gun to kill Adam.
麻烦把烟给我好吗？
May I please have a cigarette?
我要报警
I'm trying the police.
妈的
Shit.
这支手机只能接不能打
This was meant to receive calls, not make them.
等等 我之前也遇过
Wait a minute. This has happened before.
昨晚我离开医院后
Last night, after I finished at the hospital…
我走去开车
I was walking back to my car.
我以为只有我 显然还有别人
I thought I was alone, but I'm sure someone else was there.
那个怪物就等在那里
That thing. It was waiting for me.
- 你怎么知道要关灯？- 管他的 反正有用
- How did you know to turn off the lights? - Who cares? It worked.
- 但你怎么知道？- 直觉
- Yeah, but how did you know? - Instinct.
- 直觉？- 对
- Instinct? - Yeah.
你知道吗？你是个大骗子
You know what? You're a terrible liar.
你又认识我了
You say that like you know me.
你还有什么没说？
What else aren't you telling me?
我想想看
Let's see.
我6岁生日那天
On my sixth birthday, my best friend at that time, Scott Tibbs…
被死党拿生锈的钉子刺伤
stabbed me with a rusty nail. I didn't tell you that.
吃素的女性主义女友甩了我
I didn't tell you my last girlfriend, a feminist vegan punk…
说我太愤世嫉俗
broke up with me because she thought I was too angry.
- 我有一个脚趾甲 - 够了
- I haven't told you that one of my toenails… - Stop it.
- 你知道要关灯 - 随便
- You knew to turn off these lights. - Whatever.
真是幼稚
I'm dealing with a juvenile.
- 你想知道？- 对
- You wanna know? - Yeah.
你自己看
Here it is.
天哪
Oh, God!
这是哪来的？
Where did you get this?
在你女儿的照片后面
It was in your wallet, behind the photo of your daughter.
- 你怎么不拿给我看？- 我不忍心
- Why didn't you show me this before? - I couldn't.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你把她们怎么了！
What are you doing to them, you bastard?
好 我得思考
Okay, I got to think now.
你不必用枪也能杀亚当
Think about this: You don't need a gun to kill Adam.
当血液中含有巨毒 唯有
When there is that much poison in your blood, the only thing left to do…
自尽才能解脱
is shoot yourself.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
喂！
Hey!
你搞什么？
What the hell are you doing?
亚当 听我说 你跟我演出戏
Adam, listen to me. I want you to play along with me on this.
懂了吗？
You got that?
所以你 还想抽烟吗？
So, you still want that cigarette?
好啊
Yeah. Sure.
好了 我下手了
There, I've done it!
我照暗示毒死他了
I've killed him with the poison, just like you wanted!
我的家人呢？在哪里？
Now where is my family? Where are they?
什么？
What?
- 我被电了 - 什么？
- I just got electrocuted. - What?
- 那是大好机会 - 你没听见吗？
- That was our way out. - Did you hear what I said?
帮我把它拿掉 快点
Get this thing off me. Get it off!
- 别演戏了 - 难不成我会故意拆穿你？
- Stop acting. - You think I would make that up…
是你出的出意 他妈叫我演戏
just to mess up your stupid, fucking charade?
够了
All right, that's it!
妈的！
Damn it!
我想起来了
I remember everything now.
我想起事情经过了
I remember how I got here.
有人吗？
Is someone there?
我听见你了
I can hear you.
搞什么？
What the…
是谁？谁在那里？
Who is that? Who's in there?
快出来 小心我宰了你
Come on out! I'll kill you, you motherfucker.
- 是谁？- 爹地？
- Who is this? - Daddy?
- 黛安娜？- 爹地 是你吗？
- Diana? - Daddy, is that you?
对 就是我
Yeah, baby, it's me. I'm here.
爹地我好怕
I'm scared, Daddy.
别怕 不会有事的
Don't worry, honey. Everything's going to be okay.
- 妈咪呢？- 她在旁边
- Where is Mommy? - She's here with me.
让我跟她说 叫妈咪听电话
Let me talk to her, sweetie. Okay? Put Mommy on.
那个坏人在这里
The bad man from my room is here.
他绑住我们
He has us tied up…
而且他有枪
and he has a gun.
什么坏人？
What man?
你快回来
Please come home, Daddy.
喂？
Hello?
黛安娜？
Diana?
- 劳瑞 - 艾丽？是你吗？
- Larry? - Ali?
亚当在那里吗？
Is Adam there?
你怎么知道
How do you know?
艾丽 这是怎么回事？
Ali, what is going on?
不要相信亚当的话
Don't believe Adam's lies.
他认识你 他早就认识你了
He knows you. He knew all about you before today.
喂？艾丽？
Hello? Ali?
喂？
Hello?
去你的
God damn you!
你敢碰她们 我就宰了你 听到没？
If you so much as lay a finger on them, I'll kill you! Do you hear me?
混蛋！我宰了你
You son of a bitch. I'll kill you!
她们还好吗？
Are they okay?
我太太提到你的名字
My wife, she mentioned your name.
她说什么？
What did she say?
她叫我
She told me…
不要相信你
not to believe you.
相信我什么？
Believe me about what?
她说你认识我
She told me you know me.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你知道我是谁
You know who I am.
别说慌了！你这个骗子
Stop the lies. You're a liar!
我要听实话
I need to know the truth!
我是骗子？
I'm a liar?
你昨晚做了什么？
What did you do last night, Lawrence?
在医院救治病童吗？
Work at a hospital? Saving sick children?
你说你昨晚出门后去了医院
You told me that after you left your house last night, you went to work at a hospital.
本来就是
That's because it's the truth.
不对 你老婆说得没错
No, it's not. Your wife is right, Larry.
你在停车场不是被拍照？
You don't recall getting your picture taken in that parking lot?
我可以证明你昨晚没去医院
I can prove that you didn't go anywhere near a hospital last night.
那也不是第一次
It's not the first time I've done it either, Larry.
我跟拍你几天了
I've been taking pictures of you for a few days now.
我
Why?
我专门拿钱跟拍你这种有钱人
Wanna know what I do? I get paid to take pictures of rich guys like you…
上九流宾馆跟秘书乱搞
who go to seedy, out-of-the-way motels to fuck their secretaries.
昨晚我去你家看着你出门
Last night I went to your house. I watched you leave.
我跟踪你
I followed you…
一直跟到那个破宾馆
all the way to that shitbag hotel.
你一直带在身上？
You've had these with you the whole time?
它们跟锯子摆在一起
I found them in there, with the hacksaws.
我也莫名其妙
I don't know how they got there.
Yeah, right. You're so full of it!
承认吧 我们都一样 但我的相机不会说慌
Face it, Larry, we're both bullshitters, but my camera isn't.
它只会呈现事实
It doesn't know how to lie. It shows you what's put right in front of it.
你进去做了什么？
Just out of curiosity, what did you do in that motel room?
那么快就出来
You got out of there pretty fast.
你知道我在家还call我？
Why did you deem it necessary to page me when you knew I was at home?
我怕你不能来
I didn't know if you were gonna make it.
我指定了联络时间
But I gave you a precise time at which to page me.
你不能那样
You can't do that.
我不懂这种事的规矩
It's not like I know the rules for this sort of stuff.
戈登医生 怎么了？
What's wrong, Dr.Gordon?
听着 我不该找你来的
Look, it was wrong of me to make you come here.
- 我以为我们 - 别说了
- But I thought we… - Please.
别说了
I'm sorry.
- 你有告诉别人吗？- 没有
- You tell anyone you were here? - No.
喂
Hello?
- 找你的 - 我？
- It's for you. - For me?
喂？
Hello?
我知道你的丑事 医生
I know what you're doing, Doctor.
- 我得走了 - 怎么回事？
- I have to go. - What happened?
我得走了
I got to go.
- 是谁？- 谁是谁？
- Who was it? - Who was what?
谁雇用你跟拍我？
The person who paid you to follow me? Who was it?
他自称鲍伯 钱也付了
He calls himself Bob and he gives me the money up front.
一晚200
$200 a night.
早知如此就开天价
If I knew I was gonna end up here, I would've asked for more.
什么意思？你看到我被捉？
Does that mean you saw what happened to me?
我只看到你上车
What I saw was you get into your car. That's it.
我没问你的名字 我不认识你
I didn't ask your name. I didn't know who you were.
我不知道我们是怎么来的
I don't know how I got here, I don't know how you got here.
我只是拍照 回家洗照片
I just took the shots and went straight home to develop.
然后就被链在
Next thing I know, I'm chained to a pipe…
这个破厕所里
in some pre-historic bathroom…
和我跟拍的人对看
staring at the guy I've been taking shots of all night.
就是你雇主捉我们来的
Clearly, whoever paid you to take pictures of me is the one who put us here.
- 或许吧 - 你说“或许”是什么意思？
- Maybe. - What do you mean maybe?
根本就是 他的长相呢？
Of course it is. What did he look like?
- 就是个男人 - 是高是瘦是胖？
- He was just a guy. - Was he tall, skinny, obese, what?
我没注意长相
I don't take notes about his appearance.
- 你一定有印象 - 没有
- You must remember something of him. - I can't.
完全没有？
You don't remember a thing about the guy?
- 我说过 - 算了！我放弃
- I told you… - For fuck's sake! I give up!
他是个高大的黑人 脖子有疤
He's a tall, black guy. He's got a scar around his neck, okay?
泰普
Tapp!
泰普警探
Det. Tapp.
雇用我的人可不是条子
The guy who paid me to take these photos was not a cop.
不 他被解职了
No. He was discharged from the police force.
搭档死后他崩溃了 但他还是来骚扰我
He broke down after his partner was killed. But that didn't stop him from harassing me.
他走火入魔了
The guy became obsessed.
他相信我有涉案 他疯了
He convinced himself I must have somehow been involved with the murders…
而你帮了他
And you helped him.
你收钱侵犯我的隐私
You took money from him to invade my privacy.
- 你怎么能这样 - 这叫讨生活
- How could you do that? - Call it my need to eat.
是啊
Right.
你知道吗？你不是受害者
You know what? You're not a victim of this game…
- 你是帮凶 - 是吗？
- you're a part of it. - Really?
这个条子觉得你是主谋
Obviously this cop thinks you're the one behind it all.
我说过他不是警察
I told you, he's not a cop.
- 他是个人渣 跟你一样 - 你是比较气
- He's a bottom feeder. Just like you. - What are you more pissed off about?
我偷拍你
That I took some shots of you…
还是气我拍到你背叛老婆
or that I took shots while you were cheating on your wife?
- 我没有背叛她 - 你管我怎么想
- I did not cheat on her! - Why do you care what I think anyway?
我管你玩性爱游戏
I don't give a crap if you covered yourself in peanut butter…
搞15P
and had a 15 hooker gang-bang.
怎么会这样？
How did I get here?
事情本来好好的
I had everything in order.
我过得好好的
My whole life was in perfect order.
亲爱的 你还好吗？
Sweetheart, are you okay?
你现在一定要很勇敢
Mommy just needs you to be really strong right now.
我不会让你受到伤害 懂吗？
I'm not going to let anybody hurt you. You got that?
我们一言为定
That's my good girl.
昨晚你家里还有别人吗？
Hey, was there someone else at your house last night…
- 除了你的妻女以外 - 没有
- besides your wife and daughter? - No.
我拍到一个人
Well, there's someone here.
我认识他 是赛普
I know him. Zep!
他叫赛普
His name is Zep.
是院里的护理员
He's an orderly in my hospital.
赛普 你这个变态
You perverted little psychopath.
我一定要看你遭天谴
I'm gonna take great pleasure in seeing you pay for this!
混帐王八蛋
You bastard! Fuck!
你看
Look.
时间要到了
We're out of time.
- 乖 - 妈咪救我
- It's okay. - Mommy, help me.
戈登医生的时间到了
Dr. Gordon's time is up.
我该动手了 而且
Now I gotta do what I've gotta do, and…
恐怕得由你来宣告他失败
I'm afraid it has to be you that tells him he failed.
赛普是你吗？我知道是你 混蛋
Is that you, Zep, you bastard! I know it's you, you son of a bitch!
- 劳瑞？- 艾丽？
- Larry. - Ali?
你失败了
You failed.
喂？
Hello?
别动 不准起来
Don't move! Stay on the ground.
电话给我
Give me the phone.
快拿来
Give it to me!
- 劳瑞 - 艾丽
- Larry? - Ali!
- 你还好吗？- 不好
- Honey, are you all right? - No.
我们不 坐下！
No, we're not… Get down!
你在哪里？
Larry, where are you?
不知道 我被囚禁在一个地方
I don't know. I'm being held captive in a room somewhere.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
- 艾丽 对不起 - 我们需要你
- I'm so sorry, Ali. - Larry, we need you here.
一切都是我不好
I'm sorry for everything. It's my fault.
原谅我 你带给我幸福
Please forgive me. I've always been happy with you.
妈咪
Mommy.
艾丽！
Ali!
妈咪 救命啊
Mommy, help me.
不准动
Freeze!
不要啊
Oh, no.
该死
What the fuck?
戈登太太？
Mrs. Gordon?
黛安娜
Diana?
我要去杀了你老公
I'm gonna kill your husband now, Mrs. Gordon.
劳伦斯
Lawrence!
劳伦斯 快起来
Lawrence, get up!
劳伦斯 起来
我需要你
I need you.
谢天谢地 我以为你死了
Thank God! I thought you were dead.
- 他用电电我 - 我就说吧
- He electrocuted me. - I told you.
我刚才也是 我没骗你吧？
The same thing happened to me, see? I wasn't lying, see?
去死吧
Fuck this shit!
混蛋！我宰了你
I'm gonna kill you, you sick asshole.
不
No!
劳伦斯 你冷静
Lawrence, calm down.
- 会有办法的 - 你闭嘴！
- There must be a way out of here. - I can't be calm!
我的家人需要我
My family needs me.
天哪
No, God!
别这样
Stop it.
劳伦斯 你冷静
Lawrence, please calm down.
会有办法的
There's a way out of here. There's a way out.
不要！天哪！
No! Oh, my God!
你想干什么？
What are you doing?
劳伦斯 你想干什么？
Lawrence, what are you doing?
等等 你
What are you…
天哪 天哪
Oh, my God!
劳伦斯 不要
Lawrence, don't! No!
不要啊 我求求你
Lawrence, please! I'm begging you.
劳伦斯 不是我害你的
Lawrence, it's not me who did this to you.
- 你非死不可 - 不！我想活
- You have to die. - No, I want to live.
- 对不起 - 我想活
- I'm sorry. - I want to live.
我的家人
My family…
我动手了！
I've done it!
让我见她们
Now show them to me.
谢谢警官
Thank you very much, Officer.
- 劳瑞？- 打通了吗？
- Larry? - Did you get through to him?
还是没人接
There's still no answer.
不要紧 我报警了 放心
It's all right. I've called the police. Everything's okay.
混蛋！我宰了你 我宰了你
You bastard! I'll fucking kill you.
你这个混蛋 我宰了你
You fucking bastard! I'll fucking kill you!
来不及了
You're too late.
- 为什么？- 这是游戏规则
- Why? - It's the rules.
你没事的 我只伤了你的肩膀
You're going to be all right. You're just wounded in the shoulder.
我得去求援
I have to go and get help.
不要离开我 不要
Don't leave me. No!
放心 我会带人回来 我保证
Don't worry, I'll bring someone back. I promise.
钥匙
Key.
Key!
因铎先生
Hello, Mr. Hindle…
在医院里人称 赛普
or as they called you around the hospital: Zep.
我要你做个选择
I want you to make a choice.
你的体内有慢性毒药
There's a slow-acting poison coursing through your system…
我才有解毒剂
that only I have the antidote for.
你会杀害一对母女以自救吗
Will you murder a mother and her child to save yourself?
戈登医生的时间到了
Dr.Gordon's time is up.
戈登太太
Mrs. Gordon?
如果会的话 规则如下
Listen carefully, if you will. There are rules.
- 为什么？- 这是游戏规则
- Why? - It's the rules.
铁链的钥匙在浴缸里
Key to that chain is in the bathtub.
这个人很有意思 他叫约翰
He's a very interesting person. His name's John.
有无法开刀的前叶肿瘤
He has an inoperable frontal lobe tumor…
我正在受病魔侵袭
Sick from the disease eating away at me inside.
看来拼图杀人狂
Sounds like our friend Jigsaw.
我恨身在福中不知福的人
Sick of people who don't appreciate their blessings.
喜欢近距离观赏他的变态游戏
Looks like our guy likes to book himself front row seats to his sick games.
马克
Hello, Mark.
戈登医生 我想玩个游戏
Dr. Gordon, I want to play a game.
人活着多半不知感激
Most people are so ungrateful to be alive.
你以后不会了
But not you. Not anymore.
游戏结束
Game over.
别走！别走
Don't!